Guide to the Yale University Library Materials Concerning Events and Exhibits
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University Library materials concerning events and exhibits
1996-2008
RU 368
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.29
214.4
The materials consist of invitations, posters, programs, Four photographs of Simon Samoeil, curator of the Near East Collection, Yale University Library, providing a guided tour of the "Middle Eastern and Islamic Cuisine" exhibition in Sterling Memorial Library, and videorecordings documenting Yale University Library activities, events, exhibits, and functions.
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-A (YRG 32-A), Central records of the Yale University Library and records of the librarian
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of invitations, posters, programs, Four photographs of Simon Samoeil, curator of the Near East Collection, Yale University Library, providing a guided tour of the "Middle Eastern and Islamic Cuisine" exhibition in Sterling Memorial Library, and videorecordings documenting Yale University Library activities, events, exhibits, and functions.
Academic libraries; Yale University. Library -- Exhibitions; Yale University. Library
- Invitations and program, 1997-1998; Accession 1998-A-068
  - Invitations to dedication programs of library activities, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Program for "Reflecting on the Legacy of Cinque and Martin Luther, 1998 (Box 1)
- Programs and memorabilia associated with library activities, 1996-1999; Accession 2001-A-002
  - Programs and memorabilia associated with library activities, 1996-1999 (Box 1)
- Poster titled "From Books to Bytes: Navigating the Language, The Oxford English Dictionary Then and Now", 2000; Accession 2001-A-035
  - Poster titled "From Books to Bytes: Navigating the Language, The Oxford English Dictionary Then and Now", 2000 (Box 1)
- "Reading History and Writing Fiction: A Life in Books" [videorecording], 2008 May 9; Accession 2008-A-189 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Sponsored by the Yale University Library, two renowned authors Booker Prize winner Penelope Lively and Pulitzer Prize winner David McCullough offer their perspectives on their craft. The event was moderated by University Librarian Alice Prochaska
  Lively began her career as an author of children's books. Her works include "The Ghost of Thomas Kempe," for which she received the Carnegie Medal, and "A Stitch in Time," which won the Whitbread Award. She has been nominated three times for the Booker Prize, an annual contemporary fiction award presented to writers in the British Commonwealth or Ireland, and she won it in 1987 for her novel "Moon Tiger." She is a fellow of the Royal Society for Literature and a member of PEN and the Society of Authors. She was designated as an officer of the Order of the British Empire in 1989 by Queen Elizabeth II and was promoted to commander in 2001. Her most recent novel, "Consequences," was published in June 2007
  McCullough has been called the "master of the art of narrative history." A 1955 graduate of Yale College, he has twice won both the National Book Award and the Pulitzer Prize. In December of 2006, he received the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the nation's highest civilian honor. His 2001 biography of patriot and founding father John Adams has been turned into a seven-part mini-series by HBO.The DVD includes an interview with McCullough that was filmed at Sterling Memorial Library this past summer
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
  - "Reading History and Writing Fiction: A Life in Books", 2008 May 9; computer files (DVD-Video)
    General note
    Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
    - Use copy, optical disk (DVD) (Box 1U)
- "Celebrating the 80th Anniversary of the OED", 2008 October 1; Accession 2009-A-124 (Box 1)
  The materials are open for research.
  The Yale University Library and Oxford University Press sponsored a panel lecture on October 1, 2008 to celebrate the 80th birthday of the Oxford English Dictionary (OED), the comprehensive dictionary of the English language. The speakers were Fred Shapiro, Simon Winchester, Jesse Sheidlower, and Ammon Shea. Each brought unqiue and engaging insights to this discussion of the history, function and future of the dictionary
  The OED was formally lauched June 6, 1928, and it took 70 years to compile the initial 10 volumes, which contained almost 415,000 words. Former British Prime Minister Stanley Baldwin called the creation of the OED "the greatest enterprise of its kind in history." Today, the OED fills 20 volumes and weighs 137 pounds. It has been available on the Internet since 2000 as the OED Online
  - SML Panel Discussion: The Oxford English Dictionary", 2008 October 1; computer files (DVD-Video)
    - Use copy, optical disk (DVD) (Box 1U)
- Photographs from a tour of the exhibit "Middle Eastern Islamic Cuisine", 2007; Accession 2012-A-060
  The 2012-A-060 accession consists of one folder containing four photographs of Simon Samoeil, curator of the Near East Collection, Yale University Library, providing a guided tour of the "Middle Eastern and Islamic Cuisine" exhibition in Sterling Memorial Library. The exhibition ran from February 1 through April 19, 2007 in the Sterling Cloiser.
  The guided tour was part of the workshop "Sweet & Savory: Teaching to the Senses at the Corssroads of Civilizations" that was organized by PIER (Programs in International Educational Resources) and the Council on Middle Eastern Studies at the MacMillan Center, Yale University.
  All four photographs were taken by Anthony Riccio, Access Services Administration, Sterling Memorial Library.
  - Simon Samoeil, former curator of the Near East Collection, Yale University Library, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Simon Samoeil with employees of the Near East Collection, left to right: Abdelwahab Mustafa, Majda Deeb, Samoeil, Abdul Ahad Hannawi, and Ahmed Ramadan, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Simon Samoeil with Abdul Hannawi, Majda Deeb and Ahmed Ramadan, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Simon Samoeil with Abe Parrish, Map Department, Yale University Library, 2007 (Box 1)
- Sterling Memorial Library Nave re-dedication, 2014 September 5; Accession 2015-A-024
  - Programs, 2014 September 5 (Box 1, Folder 1)